## Sergiy Savostin

07361549657 • sergiy@savostin.com Facebook Linkedin Github Isleworth, Greater London

#### **Personal statement**

I've started my journey to IT back when a computer was hard to come across. From a curious teenager who was keen on discovering something new every single day, over the last 30 years I have brought myself to become an experienced full stack developer.

I still haven't lost my passion to learn, easily and with pleasure, drawing something new from every task I've completed. Whether it's a pet project or an enterprise endeavour, I always look for (and find) the best solution to a problem based on business requirements, resources, and the available technology stack.

Working in a boot-strapped company that has become almost like a family, I have realised that being a good professional is only half of the success formula. Playing within a team of talented individuals, sharing one's knowledge and experience are key to a rapid growth in the constantly changing markets. My goal is to become part of such a team of professionals and work on high-profile projects.

I'm not afraid of making mistakes, as it is a good opportunity to learn from them. I respect the advice and opinions of others, but at the same time I am not afraid to make decisions on my own.

I feel enthusiastic about bringing all my experience in software development to the table, like backend systems design, REST API written in PHP/Node.js, database architecture implemented in MySQL, MariaDB, and Clickhouse; client UX/UI with Javascript, D3.js, Crossfilter, Hightcharts.js, React and many other tools and frameworks I have laid my hands on during my career.

### **Employment History**

# Full stack Developer, WellDone Creative Software, UK 2009 - Present

- Developing and managing corporate websites and web applications (PHP, MySQL, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, D3.js).
- Developing a Windows VPS hosting service, including a billing system and a management console (Proxmox, KVM, Powershell, PHP).
- Designing and managing a 1Tb+ statistical data service (MySQL, Clickhouse, PHP, D3.is, Node.is, API).
- Developing native libraries for the company's software products (C/C++, SQLite, OpenSSL).
- Developing desktop betting software (Qt/C++, OpenSSL)

 Integration of the company's products and apps with third-party services, platforms, and APIs: Stipe, PayPal, SMS gateway, mass mail; ticket system; CRM, MODx, SMF, Cloudflare, several APIs (JSON, XML/SOAP, REST).

# Head of Internet Services, Kits Telecom ISP, Zaporizhzhya, Ukraine 2007 - 2009

Supervised a team of systems engineers and network administrators in the rolling out of a new cable Internet service provider. The company was later acquired by a national ISP.

## Head of Web Development, Market ISP, Zaporizhzhya, Ukraine 2004 - 2007

Managed a team of web developers and designers working on commercial websites.

# Senior Full Stack Developer, Marka ISP, Zaporizhzhya, Ukraine

Started as a junior Full Stack developer and was promoted to the senior position. Building business presentation websites, online stores, e-commerce websites, chats.

### Projects done by my own

- BetFair graphs aggregator
  - Backend: Node.js + Highcharts.js + MySQL for historical graphs generation
  - Backend: Node.is + Restify + MySQL/Bookshelf + Express.is for API
  - Backend: Node.js + PHP + Websockets + Nginx for realtime graphs microservices / proxying 3rd party APIs
  - Frontend: jQuery + Moment.js + web-sockets
- BetFair historical data analysis tool
  - Backend: Node.js + MySQL + Clickhouse for report creation
  - Backend: Node.js + Restify + MySQL for API
  - Frontend: D3.js + Crypto.js for visualisations
- Windows VPS hosting
  - Backend: PHP + MySQL for control panel and API
  - Backend: PHP + Proxmox + Power-shell for VPS cluster management
  - Frontend: ¡Query
- BetFair historical data plugin backend and libs
  - Backend: PHP + MySQL for 1Tb+ database (collecting and processing the data), API for the software, billing (purchasing data, user-bound data encryption, MySQL-SQLite data sync)
  - Libs and DLLs: C/C++ + SQLite + jQuery + D3.js (logging system, logs viewer)
- MarketLocator Betting desktop (MacOS, Windows) software
  - Qt/C++, OpenSSL
- WellDoneSoft billing
  - Backend: PHP + MvSQL
  - Frontend: React.js + Handlebars
- Developing projects architecture, number of \*nix servers installations and full administration (Nginx, MySQL, Bash, PHP, Perl, Powershell, Javascript)

#### **Skills**

Programming Languages: PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, C/C++/Qt, HTML, CSS,

bash, Powershell, SQL.

Run-time environments: Node.js.

Frameworks and web components: React/React Hooks, jQuery, D3.js, Axios,

Charts.js, Highcharts.js.

**Databases:** MySQL/MariaDB, SQLite, Clickhouse. **Operating Systems:** Linux, Windows, MacOS.

Architectures: Microservices, Event-driven, Client-Server, Serverless.

Cloud systems: AWS.

Virtualisation: Proxmox, Virtualbox, Docker.

APIs: REST, SOAP, OpenAPI, JSON.

CI/CD: Jenkins.

Collaboration Tools: Jira, Git, Trello.

**Graphics Editors:** Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Sketch.

Languages: English, Russian, Ukrainian.

#### **Education**

### Zaporizhzhian National Technical University, Ukraine

(1991 - 1996)

Bachelor degree in Electronics design engineer

#### **Hobbies & Interests**

Hiking, cycling, traveling, volleyball, dioramas and miniatures modelling, writing music, books publishing.